（大石(おおいし)）ええ 園崎(そのざき)組が総動員で
あなたを捜してるらしいんです
Yes, the Sonozaki group has
gotten together to look for you.
（ﾚﾅ）敵も なりふり
かまわなくなったってことですね
That means the enemy doesn't
care about their position, right?
つまり 話を整理すると…
To clarify things...
...they are after Takano-san's
scrapbook, which you have.
連中の狙いは あなたが
持っている鷹野(たかの)さんのスクラップ帳
I believe so.
（ﾚﾅ）多分…
それには オヤシロさまのたたりの
真相が書かれてあり
So the truth of Oyashiro-sama's
curse is written in it...
...and it'll help solve Hinamizawa's
serial mysterious deaths?
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)連続怪死事件を
解く手がかりになると？
はい
Yes.
（ﾚﾅ）そして ヤツらは
オヤシロさま信仰を復活させるため
And to revive religious
belief in Oyashiro-sama...
大がかりな細菌テロを
仕掛けようとしているんです
...they're planning
a large bioterrorist attack.
私は 彼らが実行に移すＸデーが
近い気がしてなりません
I have a feeling
that day will be soon.
（大石）分かりました
I understand.
こちらのほうでも
なんとかしてみます
I'll see what I can do.
（大石）
そんな とんでもない計画なら―
If it really is such
a massive plan...
...then there should
be hints about it.
必ず
どこかに手がかりがあるはずです
（ﾚﾅ）お願いします
（大石）あっ それと もうひとつ
Please.
And one more thing.
鷹野さんのことで
変わった話がありましてね
We found out something
strange about Takano-san.
変わった話ですか？
Something strange?
竜宮(りゅうぐう)さん
綿流しの晩を覚えてますか？
Ryugu-san, do you
remember Cotton Drifting night?
That evening...
あの晩…
...you and your friends talked
to Tomitake-san and Takano-san.
あなたの仲良し５人組と
富竹(とみたけ)さん 鷹野さんの７人で―
談笑してますよね？
（ﾚﾅ）ええ
Yes.
実はですね
岐阜県警さんの鑑識では―
To tell the truth, according
to the Gifu prefecture police...
...the body was found more
than 24 hours after death.
死後24時間以上って
出ちゃったらしいんですよ
でも それだと
あの祭りの前の晩には―
Then that means she was killed
the night before the festival.
殺されてることになるんです
（ﾚﾅ）それって…
That means...
つまり
早い話が 綿流しの日には―
In short, it means she was dead
already on Cotton Drifting day.
鷹野さん
もう死んでることになるんですよ
So that person you met festival
night could've been a zombie.
だから
あの祭りの晩に会った彼女は―
実は
ゾンビだったのかな …なんてね
Just kidding.
まあ あちらの鑑識の
ちょいとしたポカでしょう
It might just be
the department's silly mistake.
あっ もしもし？
（ﾚﾅ）あっ… あっ はい
Hello?
Yes, um...
あの… とにかく
ヤツらの陰謀を食い止めてください
Anyway,
please stop their conspiracy.
I'll hide for a while.
私は しばらく身を潜めます
I'll contact you again.
また連絡します
Oishi-san!
（熊谷(くまがい)）大石さん
（大石）うん？
（熊谷）
やっぱり ヤバそうなヤマっす
It's pretty dangerous.
The Sonozakis' Tatsuyoshi
Kasai is looking for Rena Ryugu.
竜宮レナを捜してるのは
園崎組 葛西辰由(かさい たつよし)
葛西？
園崎茜(あかね)の懐刀じゃないですか！
Kasai!
He's Akane Sonozaki's
elite assistant.
情報屋の間でも
竜宮レナが園崎組にとって―
It's a rumor among
the affiliates that Rena Ryugu...
相当 都合の悪いものを
握ってるんじゃないかと―
...has something highly
inconvenient for the Sonozakis.
専らのウワサです
う～ん… 覆面を
竜宮家に張り付かせてください
Place undercover cops
at Ryugu's house!
実は 竜宮レナは
家の金を何十万か盗んで―
Actually, it seems she stole
hundreds of her family's money...
雲隠れしているらしいんです
...and has hidden herself.
バカ野郎！ なんで
そいつを早く言わないんだ！
You idiot! Why didn't
you tell me that earlier?
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 04: EARTH INVASION
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
（圭一(けいいち)）レナが雲隠れ？
Rena hid herself?
Plus, the police
are looking for her.
（魅音(みおん)）おまけに
警察がレナの行方を捜してるって
（圭一）まさか 俺たちの
隠した死体が見つかったとか？
Could it be they've
found the corpses we hid?
（魅音）ああ 実は あの死体ね
園崎家のほうで―
To tell you the truth...
...I had those bodies disposed
at a Sonozaki secret area.
秘密の場所に処分させてもらったの
（圭一）えっ？
（魅音）私たちが
死体を隠した あの山林
This summer, there seems
to be a plan to deforest...
今年の夏に大規模な伐採計画が
あるらしいんだわ
...the mountain forest
where we hid the bodies.
だから 私のほうで
先に手を回させてもらったってわけ
So I went ahead
and took care of it.
そっか
じゃ どうして警察がレナを？
I see.
Then why are
the police looking for Rena?
分からない
I don't know.
But I've told my Okinomiya family
to secure Rena's safety...
とにかく 警察よりも先に
レナの身柄を確保するよう―
...as soon as possible.
興宮(おきのみや)の家には伝えてある
本家なら120パーセント
警察からレナを守れるから
The main house can protect
Rena from the police 120%.
Yeah. If you find Rena,
you have to contact me.
うん レナが見つかったら
必ず連絡くれよな
（魅音）うん 分かった
Yeah, I got it.
Where did Rena go?
レナのヤツ
どこに行っちまったんだ？
あっ もしかして…
Could it be...
（男Ａ）おい
よく この辺で遊んでるらしいぞ
Hey, it seems like she
plays around here a lot.
（男Ｂ）さすがに
こんな時間には いねえだろう
But I don't think
she'll be here at this time.
（男Ａ）分かんねえぞ
（ﾚﾅ）ハッ…
How do you know?
Hey, shine your
light more over there.
（男Ａ）もっとそっち照らしてみろ
（男Ｂ）ああ
Okay.
Do you see anything?
（男Ａ）どうだ？
（男Ｂ）いや よく見えねえよ
I can't see.
（男Ａ）ちゃんと見ろよ
（ﾚﾅ）ハッ…
Look closely.
Should we go farther in?
（男Ｂ）もうちょっと奥行くか？
（男Ａ）うん
（男Ａ）
アツシです　感度良好… はい
This is Atsushi.
Reception is good.
Yes. The storehouse?
穀倉(ごぐら)？ はい 了解です
- Okay, got it.
- What happened?
（男Ｂ）どうした？
（男Ａ）竜宮レナは穀倉らしい
Rena Ryugu seems
to be at the storehouse.
（男Ａ）目撃情報があったそうだ
It seems there was a witness.
（男Ｂ）おいおい どうすんだよ？
Hey, hey. What'll we do?
The head said to bring her
back no matter what it takes.
（男Ａ）とにかく是が非でも
ひっ捕まえて 連れてこいって―
旦那の命令だ
追っかけるしかねえだろう
We just gotta chase her.
（男Ｂ）ああ… まいったな
Oh, man.
私が穀倉にいる？
I'm at the storehouse?
まさか…
Could it be?
So that person you met festival
night could've been a zombie.
（大石）だから
あの祭りの晩に会った彼女は―
実は
ゾンビだったのかな …なんてね
Just kidding.
As expected,
Takano-san's theory is correct.
（ﾚﾅ）やっぱり…
鷹野さんの仮説は正しい
I won't give up.
負けるもんか…
絶対に… 絶対にヤツらなんかに…
Never. Never to them.
Rena!
（圭一）レナ！
（ﾚﾅ）今度は圭一君か
Now it's Keiichi-kun, huh?
（ﾚﾅ）
ここも もう安全じゃないから―
It's not safe here anymore,
so I'm about to leave.
今から場所を変えるとこなの
I don't want you
to know where, so don't follow me.
圭一君にも知られたくないから
ついてこないで
レナ！ お前 どうしたんだよ？
その首 血だらけじゃないか
Rena! What happened?
Your neck is covered in blood!
Oh, this?
ああ これ？
大したことないから大丈夫だよ
It's nothing. I'm fine.
レナ…
（ﾚﾅ）今日の夕方ね―
Rena...
This afternoon, I went to the place
where we hid the two bodies.
私 あの２人の死体を隠した場所に
行ってみたの
そしたら どうだったと思う？
（圭一）あっ…
And then guess what?
なかったの 死体
The bodies were gone.
Somebody dug
them up and took them.
誰かが掘り返して
死体を持ち去った
No, that's...
いや それは…
（ﾚﾅ）あの場所に
隠したことを知っているのは―
The only ones who
knew we hid them there...
あの場所に
居合わせた人間しかいない
...are the people who were there.
えっと… だから…
Um, that's...
それは…
（ﾚﾅ）魅ぃちゃんだよ
It's Mi-chan.
あっ… 違う そうじゃないって！
No! That's not true.
魅ぃちゃんが私を売ったんだよ
Mi-chan betrayed me.
魅音がレナを売ることなんて
絶対にない！
How could Mion betray you?
どうして魅ぃちゃんの肩持つの？
Why are you
supporting Mi-chan?
あ… あの死体が
なくなっていたのは―
The bodies aren't there
because Mion dug them up, but...
確かに 魅音が掘り返したからだ
So it was her!
やっぱり そうじゃない！
あの辺り一帯を伐採する計画が
あるってことが分かったんだよ
She found out that there was
a plan to deforest that area.
So Mion dug up the bodies
in order to protect you.
だから 魅音は レナを守るために
死体を掘り返してくれたんだ
フフッ… そんなの
口から出任せに決まってるよ
That has to be a lie.
Then what
should we have done?
じゃ どうすりゃよかったんだよ？
そのままにしとくのか？
Should we have
kept them there?
How could we do that?
そんなこと
できるわけねえだろう！
Who cares now.
（ﾚﾅ）もういいや
圭一君には真実を教えてあげるよ
I'll tell you the truth.
The real truth that
I haven't told you.
私が圭一君に話してない本当の真実
The truth?
真実？
To tell the truth, the real
identity of the parasite is an alien.
実はね 寄生虫の正体は宇宙人なの
A-Aliens?
えっ？ 宇宙人？
（ﾚﾅ）ヤツらは寄生することで
人体を支配してきた
They were controlling
the human body by living off of it.
But eventually,
a clever human was born...
だが 時折 勘のいい人間が生まれ
その支配の実体を暴こうとした
...and tried to uncover
the situation behind the parasitism.
They got rid of that person...
ヤツらは それを取り除き
三四(みよ)さんのコピーを生み…
...and created a copy
of Miyo-san and me.
私のコピーを生んだ
アア…
（ﾚﾅ）私は戦うよ
I'm gonna fight.
魅ぃちゃんのことも
絶対に許さない
And I will never forgive Mi-chan.
いいかげんにしろよ レナ！
That's enough, Rena!
宇宙人なんて関係ねえし
どうだっていいよ！ 信じろよ！
Aliens don't matter,
and I don't care about them!
Trust Mion.
魅音を！ 俺たち仲間を！
（ﾚﾅ）うるさい
Trust us!
Shut up.
We made a promise
at this very place!
ここで…
この場所で約束したじゃないか！
We are...
俺たち仲間は…
（ﾚﾅ）うるさい
Shut up.
レナ！
Rena!
Shut up! Shut up!
うるさい うるさい！
うるさい うるさい うるさい！
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Shut...
うる… ウッ！ アア…
（圭一）ああっ…
レナ！
（ﾚﾅ）ウウッ…
Rena?
大丈夫か？ レナ！
Are you all right, Rena?
ウウッ… ひとつ聞いてもいい？
Can I ask you one thing?
Yeah.
Friends don't hide things
from each other, right?
（ﾚﾅ）仲間ってのは
隠し事なんて ないんだよね？
Of course.
（圭一）
当然だ 隠し事なんかしない
They don't hide things.
ウソだよ
（圭一）ウソなんか つかない
Liar.
I'm not lying.
You're lying!
ウソだ！
（ﾚﾅ）アハハハッ！ アハハッ！
What's so funny?
何が おかしいんだよ？
（ﾚﾅ）ウフフッ…
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君 私 知ってるんだよ
Keiichi-kun, I know.
I know what you were doing
before you moved here.
圭一君が引っ越してくる前に
どういうことをしてたか
知ってるんだよ
（圭一）えっ？
I had Oishi-san
research everyone.
大石さんに調べてもらったんだよ
みんなのこと
圭一君 引っ越してくる前は
とんでもない人だったんだね
You were horrible before
you moved here, weren't you?
ウフフッ…
（圭一）レナ…
Rena.
（ﾚﾅ）小さな女の子ばかり
狙ってたんだって？
You were only after
young girls, weren't you?
I can't believe such a dangerous
person was so close.
こんな危ない人が身近にいたなんて
信じられないよ
（圭一）違う！
No!
No! No!
違う！ 違う！
それは たまたまなんだ
It was just a coincidence!
（ﾚﾅ）何が“たまたま”なの？
What was a coincidence?
児童連続襲撃事件
小さな子供ばかりを狙って―
The serial child shooting case.
You only targeted children...
...and shot them with a model
gun as they passed by, right?
通りがかりに モデルガンで
撃ちつけてたんでしょう？
市内一帯は一時期 騒然
ＰＴＡが交差点ごとに立ち―
The city was once in great shock.
The PTA was at
each intersection...
集団下校にもなったんだってね
（圭一）アア…
...and children had
to walk home in groups, right?
小さな子供しか
狙わない いやらしさ
That perverted nature
of only targeting children.
そんなことして
何が楽しかったの？
What was fun about it?
But since it was fun, you kept it
up for a long time, didn't you?
でも 楽しかったから
ずっと続けてたんだよね？
But despite that,
your conscience couldn't bear it...
そのくせ 途中で
良心の呵責(かしゃく)に耐えられなくなって
ご両親と一緒に自首
...and you turned
yourself in to your parents.
（ﾚﾅ）
フフッ… 少年法って親切だよね
Juvenile law is kind, isn't it?
被害者にも
犯人の名前は公開されないし
The suspect's name
isn't revealed to the victims...
...and your father was very rich,
so he settled it with lots of money.
お父さんが大金持ちだったから
示談金をたくさん積んでくれて
You were released
with just probation.
しばらくは保護観察
When it settled down, you moved,
and all was taken care of!
ほとぼりが冷めたころに
引っ越しして 全部チャラ
It's so nice being rich.
（ﾚﾅ）いいねえ お金持ちは！
違うんだ… 違う…
No... That's not...
どうして今まで黙ってたの？
Why didn't you tell
anyone about this?
ごめん…
Sorry.
仲間ってのは
隠し事なんか なしなんでしょう？
Friends don't hide things
from each other, right?
Right?
そうでしょう？
（圭一）ウウッ…
お前は仲間なんかじゃない
You are not my friend.
When They Cry
I wonder where Rena went.
（魅音）レナのヤツ
どこ行っちゃったんだろうね？
鬼隠しに遭ったなんて―
Some people are irresponsibly
saying she's been spirited away.
いいかげんなこと
言ってる連中もいるよ
Keiichi-san, you don't
seem be doing well today.
（沙都子(さとこ)）圭一さん 今日は
元気がありませんですのことよ
（梨花(りか)）み～…
Mi.
Mion, Satoko, and Rika-chan...
沙都子に梨花ちゃんも
There's something
I want to tell you all.
話しておきたいことがある
（魅音）そう…
I see.
I had no clue something like that
happened before you moved here.
引っ越してくる前に
そんなことが あったんだ…
I'm sorry for keeping it
a secret from you all this time.
今まで隠してて悪かった
なんで そんなことを
今ごろになって―
What made you want
to tell that to us now?
わざわざ言おうと思ったわけ？
（圭一）いや…
Well...
I thought I wasn't being a good
friend by hiding things from you.
隠し事をするなんて
仲間じゃないと思って…
圭一は それをボクたちに話して
何を期待しているのですか？
Keiichi, what do you expect from
us now that you've told us this?
I don't expect anything...
期待なんて 別に…
ただ 仲間に隠し事は…
I just didn't want to keep
secrets from friends...
（魅音）仲間に隠し事って
したら いけないわけ？
Is it wrong to keep
secrets from friends?
誰だって 話したくない つらいこと
悲しいこと―
I think we all have stories we
don't want to share, of misery...
失敗したことや
思い出したくないことって―
...sadness, mistakes, or even
memories we don't want to recall.
あると思うけど
それを全部 打ち明けなければ
仲間と呼べないんなら―
If you can't call someone a friend
without divulging all that...
...then I don't want friends.
私は仲間なんて要らないね
But...
でも…
（梨花）圭一
Keiichi.
打ち明けなくていいことと
打ち明けなければならないことは
Things you don't need to share...
...are different from
things you must reveal.
違いますのです
（沙都子）そうですわ
That's right.
Plus, if you're
a good person now...
それに 今が
すばらしい人間であるならば―
...why is there a need
to feel ashamed?
どうして
恥じることがございますの？
Nothing would change the usual
fun relationship we have.
いつものように
楽しく ふざけ合える関係は―
何も変わらないのです
That's what we call friends.
（梨花）それが仲間ですから
（圭一）アア…
You guys...
みんな…
俺は 悟史(さとし)のことは何も知らない
I don't know
anything about Satoshi.
みんな 隠してたからな！
Everyone's hiding it.
We weren't hiding it...
そんなつもりじゃ…
仲間ってのは
隠し事なんか なしだろう
Friends don't hide things
from each other, right?
そうだろう？
Isn't that right?
That's why you're not my friends!
だから お前らは仲間じゃない！
（魅音）
あした 学校休んじゃイヤだよ
Don't be absent tomorrow.
Get better soon.
早く元気にな～れ！
Believe in me.
私を信じて
ウワーッ！
（圭一）アアッ…
（魅音）け… 圭ちゃん！
K-Kei-chan?
俺は… 俺は なんてことを…
What... What have I done?
Mion and Rena... I killed them.
魅音を… レナを殺してしまった
What's wrong?
（沙都子）どうしたんですの？
圭ちゃん 私は生きてるよ
Kei-chan, I'm alive.
What's happening?
（知恵(ちえ)）どうしたんですか？
ああっ！ 別に 大したことじゃ…
（沙都子）心配いりませんでしてよ
Oh, nothing much.
There's nothing to worry about.
圭一は覚えているのですか？
レナと魅音を殺したことを
Keiichi, do you remember?
That you killed Rena and Mion?
Yeah, not here,
but in a different world.
ああ ここじゃない
別のよく似た世界で…
（圭一）俺は
なぜか仲間たちに疑心暗鬼になって
Somehow I became suspicious
of my friends and killed them.
殺してしまったんだ…
Even though my friends were
apparently giving helpful words.
仲間たちは 俺に救いの言葉を
かけていたはずなのに…
Why wasn't I able
to listen to their words?
なぜ
それに耳を傾けられなかったんだ？
（圭一）どうして…
（泣き声）
Why?
Let's forgive Keiichi.
圭一を許しましょう
You were able to realize
your sin by yourself.
（梨花）圭一は 自分で
自分の罪に気づきましたのです
But no one can
understand your sin...
でも 誰も圭一の罪は分からない
許してあげることも
できませんのです
...nor can they
forgive you of your sin.
But I can forgive you of your sin.
でも ボクには
それを許すことができます
I can understand
how amazing you are.
圭一のすごさも分かるのです
（圭一）梨花ちゃん…
Rika-chan...
私には
これが奇跡であることが分かる
I understand
that this is a miracle.
You now should know
what's happening to Rena Ryugu.
今のあなたになら分かるはず
（梨花）竜宮レナが
どういうことに なっているのか
ああ あのときの俺と同じだ
Yeah, she's just
like me that one time.
She truly, truly wants
to believe in her friends but can't.
（圭一）仲間のことを信じたくて
信じたくて しょうがないのに―
信じられないんだ
But Rena tried
to save me by risking her life.
でも レナは
命を懸けて 俺を救おうと―
俺の目を覚まそうとしてくれた
She tried to help me realize.
Until the very last
moments of her life.
命を失う その瞬間まで…
I will not give up.
俺は諦めない　まだ間に合うんだ！
I still have time!
Tragedy can be avoided!
惨劇は回避できるんだ
運命は あらがえる！
Fate can be resisted!
そして つかめるんだ！
And we can take hold of it!
The so-called
future that lies ahead!
その先の未来ってやつを！
（梨花）戦おうとする意思が
こんなにも美しく神々しく―
I learned how the will to battle
can be so beautiful and divine...
...and even have
the power to overturn fate.
運命さえも覆すほどの力が
あることを 私は知った
だから 私は あなたと共に戦おう
For this reason,
I will fight with you.
（梨花）何度でも
その先の未来に たどりつくまで
No matter what, until we reach
that future that lies ahead.
（魅音）いやぁ
知恵先生も結構しつこいね
Gee, Chie-sensei
is pretty persistent.
I know.
（沙都子）ホントですわね
あっ 圭ちゃん
Kei-chan, what's the matter?
（魅音）どうしたの？
アッ！
（沙都子）キャ～ッ…
I'm sorry.
すまなかった 本当に
I'm really... sorry.
すまなかった
（魅音）な… 何がよ？ 圭ちゃん
F-For what, Kei-chan?
H-Hey, mister, I don't know
what you're talking about.
あ… あのあの…
おじさん 何のことか分かんないよ
It's okay if you don't.
分かんなくてもいい…
分かんなくてもいいから
It's okay if you don't know,
so I'm really sorry.
本当に すまなかった
俺は 魅音を… いや 仲間を―
I will never again doubt you,
Mion, nor any of my friends.
二度と疑わない
だから あの日の俺を
どうか許してくれ
So please forgive me for that day.
（魅音）圭ちゃん？
Kei-chan.
Restaurant Kichi-Ichi
Reserved For Today
（大石）おうおうおう！
こんな割烹(かっぽう)まで呼び出して―
Restaurant Kichi-Ichi
Reserved For Today
Hey, hey, hey!
Restaurant Kichi-Ichi
Reserved For Today
You call us to this nice restaurant
and tell us to believe this gossip?
その与太話を信じろっての？
You call us to this nice restaurant
and tell us to believe this gossip?
You're all not taking
our job seriously, huh?
あんたら
ウチらの商売 ナメてんの？ ええ？
Basically, this is a personal
problem between your daughter...
（熊谷）要するに 竜宮礼奈(れいな)と
そちらのお嬢さんの個人問題だから
警察に介入するなと
おっしゃりたいわけで？
...and Rena Ryugu, so
the police shouldn't intervene?
（茜）はい
Yes.
We can't do that.
そうはいきません
竜宮礼奈は
警察で保護させていただきます
The police will take
care of Rena Ryugu.
Tell us the reason the police
want to take care of Rena Ryugu.
警察が 竜宮レナを
保護したい理由をお聞かせください
そりゃ決まってるじゃないかよ
あんたらが狙ってるからだよ
It's quite obvious.
It's because you're after her.
Why do you think
we're after Rena Ryugu?
（茜）どうして当方が
竜宮礼奈を狙っているとお思いで？
Why don't you ask yourself?
（大石）あんたの胸に聞いてみろよ
（茜）葛西
Kasai.
あ～ これは？
（茜）鷹野三四のスクラップ帳です
What's this?
Miyo Takano's scrapbooks.
残念ながら―
Unfortunately, the ones she gave
Rena Ryugu are not included.
竜宮礼奈に手渡したと思われる物は
含まれておりません
Can we take a look at it?
（熊谷）拝見させていただいても？
（茜）どうぞ
Please.
（大石）ハァ…
これ 間違いなく
鷹野三四のノートなんでしょうね？
Are these really
Miyo Takano's notebooks?
Of course.
（茜）間違いありません
Do all of these
mention these things?
全部 こんな中身なんですか？
ええ そうですよ
納得いくまで ご覧ください
Yes, they do.
Look at them
until you're satisfied.
Oishi-san, it says that the "other"
world and "this" world clashed...
大石さん
“冥界と現世が激突して
霊魂が流入した”って…
...and there was
an inflow of spirits.
This is like
a problematic occult novel.
これじゃ
タチの悪いオカルト小説ですよ
これを証拠として
採用しろっていうんですか？
Are you saying we should
use this as evidence?
アア… こっちには
地底人の仕業って書いてあるよ
This one says it was caused
by underground inhabitants.
いくつか お聞きしたい
I want to ask a couple things.
Why did Miyo Takano...
鷹野三四は どうして…
（茜）鷹野三四 富竹ジロウの
死については―
Our family knows nothing...
...about the deaths of
Miyo Takano and Jiro Tomitake.
当家は一切 関知しておりません
（大石）ああ？
当家で始末して
死体が出るとお思いで？
Do you think you'll find the
bodies if you search our house?
じゃ なんで
竜宮礼奈を追ってるんだよ？
Then why are you
after Rena Ryugu?
（茜）そう見えてしまう誤解が
生じたことは こちらのミスです
It was our mistake that it
seemed like that was the case.
I will apologize for that.
その点につきましては
私より おわびさせていただきます
双方の友好の証しとして―
As proof of our friendship,
we will give you the scrapbooks.
そのスクラップ帳は
そちらに献上いたします
I'm gonna leave
the rest up to you.
（大石）
あとは もう 熊ちゃんに任すわ
Since it seems like I drank
a lot, I'll get some fresh air.
ちょっと
飲み過ぎちゃったみたいなので―
私は夜風に当たってきます
I want you to promise two things.
（熊谷）２つ約束していただきたい
I shall.
（茜）承ります
（熊谷）１点目は―
The first is if the Sonozaki family
obtains other scrapbooks...
この場にないスクラップ帳を
園崎家が入手した場合―
速やかに警察へ提出すること
...turn them in to the police.
２点目は 竜宮礼奈の
身柄を確保した場合も―
The second is if you get
a hold of Rena Ryugu...
...you must also hand
her over to the police.
必ず 警察へ引き渡すこと
Understood.
I will abide by those terms.
分かりました 条件を了承します
However, in order to protect
Rena Ryugu's rights...
ただし 竜宮礼奈の権利保全のため
当家から弁護士を派遣します
...we will assign a lawyer to her.
（茜）竜宮礼奈への尋問は―
The lawyer should be present
at all interrogations with her.
全て弁護士 立ち会いのもとで
行うこと
了解しました
Okay.
Please do not
waste our courtesy.
どうか ゆめゆめ
反故(ほご)にされることがないよう―
よろしくお願い申し上げます
（大石）ハァ…
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
Where I wandered
was the memorable classroom.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
迷い込んだのは 思い出の教室
What echoes is
the timer to despair.
響くのは 絶望へのタイマー
Where I reach is
the beginning of the end.
たどりつくのは 始まりの終わり
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 5: RETAKE.
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 05: RETAKE
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 5: RETAKE.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 05: RETAKE
Can you believe it?